CASSANDRA BIRKBECK

(406) 925-1344



cnbirkbeck@gmail.com



201 Union Ave SE Unit 210 Renton, WA 98059

EDUCATION

BA, Exercise Biology University of California - Davis, Davis, California 2007 - 2012

COMPETENCIES

Microsoft Office Suite Adobe Photoshop Adobe Lightroom PC/MAC Systems **CYMS** CPR/First Aid Certified ServSafe Food Safety Certified

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Ambitious, versatile, and professional exercise biology graduate with over 5 years experience working with youth. Committed to fostering a positive learning environment with a forward-thinking mentality. Excels in a collaborative team environment and can independently manage diverse objectives.

EXPERIENCE

Child and Youth Services US Army Garrison Benelux DFMWR | SHAPE-Belgium | Jan. 2016 - Sept.2017

Assistant Director

- Appointed as acting Director of program from Apr. 2017-Sept.2017.
- Provided program oversight and accountability for the performance of assigned staff and the safety and well being of over 100 youth daily.
- Monitored and analyzed adult/participant ratio sheets to ensure proper staffing policies are enforced.
- Oversaw the collection of accurate accounting and reporting of funds; maintained up-to-date statistical data for planning and reporting purposes.
- Developed program budget.
- Liaised with parents to ensure continued parental involvement and customer satisfaction.

Child and Youth Services US Army Garrison Benelux DFMWR SHAPE-Belgium | Apr. 2015 - Jan. 2016

CYS Program Associate: Homework Lab

- Responsible for administration and programming of Middle School / Teen Center Technology and Homework Lab.
- Provided aide to participants to strengthen their academic and learning skills in subject areas such as math, science, and English language.
- Worked with staff to develop and implement a comprehensive program to assist students in the completion of daily homework assignments, reinforce existing and develop new skills, and positively support children through recognition of their efforts.

EXPERTISE

Customer Service
Project Management
Team Leadership
Marketing
Youth Work

INTERESTS

Photography
Design
Traveling

REFERENCES

Available upon request.

EXPERIENCE

Open University | Walton Hall Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, MK7 6AA, UK | Jun. 2013 – Aug. 2014

Accounts Payable Clerk

- Responsible for entry, processing, and payment of invoices.
- Responsible for scanning invoices for Accounts Department and maintaining archives.
- Responsible for balancing of supplier accounts for the Open University.
- Responsible for multiple account reconciliations over £50,000.
- Responsible for migrating old research scripts onto a new database.

NHS Direct- 111 Service | Milton Keynes, MK14 6DY | Mar. 2013-Jun.2013

Health Advisor

- Responsible for taking calls making patients feel appreciated while providing the most accurate level of care.
- Responsible for assessing patient's symptoms to determine the correct level of care.

Red Hawk Casino | Placerville, California USA | Jul. 2010-Nov.2012

Cage Cashier

- Responsible for employee bank creation and distribution
- Responsible for balancing and adjusting marker bank, kiosk bank, chip bank, and main bank.
- Trained new employees in ESW, Chip, and Front of House banking.
- Assisted guest transactions while providing quality customer service.

Camp Adventure Youth Services | UC Davis- SAC State | Nov. 2007-Sep. 2009

Camp Counselor/ Veteran Team Training Manager

- Selected and trained various incoming applicants at Sacramento State University and UC Davis.
- Developed applicant's ability to create quality care and supervision in a youth environment.
- British Garrisons Travel Camp:
 - o Rhinedalhn Germnay- Orientation Programmed eight weeks of camp activities for camps held throughout Germany and Italy.
- Ramstien Germany AFB- Four Week British Youth Camp
 - Planned and implemented first youth camp for British children in Naples Italy.
- Griciano Naval Base- Twelve Week Youth Camp